A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, A-E FA391
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Embree, Edwin R.
  - Memoranda, 1918-1919; Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers)
    This diary discusses malaria control in Mississippi, nursing education and the poor quality of dispensaries.
    Public health; Public health nursing; Tuberculosis; United States; Hygiene; Dispensaries; Medical education -- China; Malaria
  - 1919, Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Emb 1, Frame 260, Box 130)
    Arranged by interview and visit, this diary documents the meetings and conferences Embree had with various professionals in the field of public health. The Rockefeller Foundation participates in public health and medical education.
    Dispensaries; Hygiene; Medical education; Nursing; Yellow fever; Nutrition; Public health; Tuberculosis; United States
  - Conferences, 1919; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    This diary details various conference concerning public health training, medical education, current studies and future Rockefeller Foundation programs.
    Spain; Belgium; United States; Brazil; Czechoslovakia; China; Poland; Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board; Peking Union Medical College
  - 1920, Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers) (Reel M Emb 1, Frame 489, Box 130)
    United States; Nursing; Public health; Hygiene; Medical education -- China
  - Special Memoranda, 1920; Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers)
    This brief diary documents discussions of proposals, interviews and conferences.
    Hygiene; Medical education -- China; Dispensaries; Public health; United States
  - Minutes of Staff Luncheon, 6 July 1920 - 15 December 1920; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    Human resource, administrative and office policy notes are taken during these meetings.
    Nursing; Medical education -- China; Public health; United States
  - Report, 1920; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    Report on Medical Education and Nurse Training in Central Europe.
    Public health; Poland; Nursing; Medical education -- China; Switzerland; Serbia; Czechoslovakia; Austria; Hungary; Germany; France; England
  - Conference Dockets, 1920 October; Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers)
    Lists proposal topics for discussions.
    Child welfare; Prisoners; Prisons; Psychiatry; Public health; United States
  - European Trip, 1920; Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers)
    Includes reports and recommendations, docket for executive committee meeting and exhibits.
    Europe; Medical education -- China; Nursing; Public health
  - Family Journals, 1920 June 22-October 12; Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers)
    The family journals detail Embree's trip to Europe to reestablish an exchange of research journals, scientific equipment, fellowships and bibliographic bureaus.
    Europe; Public health; World War I
  - Docket of Business, 1920; Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers)
    Brief diary detailing Rockefeller Foundation supplying European schools with medical journals and scientific equipment as well as nurse training.
    Europe; Nursing; Medical education -- China; Public health
  - Report on Vienna: Vital Statistics and the Public Health, 1920; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    Report by Robert Davis, commissioner of American Red Cross for Austria and Hungary, attached as a supplement to Embree's trip diary.
    Venereal diseases; Tuberculosis; World War I; Austria; Hospitals; Europe; Public health; Infant -- Mortality; American Red Cross
  - Log of Journey to Europe, 1920 June 22 - September 25; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    This trip diary documents Embree's meetings and conferences with various professionals in the field of public health. The Rockefeller Foundation participates in funding public health and medical education. Scientific journals and equipment exchange with Europe is detailed as well as World War I reconstruction, surveys of medical facilities and education, and vital statistics.
    Venereal diseases; Tuberculosis; Typhus fever; Croatia; Austria; Europe; Czechoslovakia; Germany; France; Libraries; Hungary; Switzerland; Public health; Serbia; Medical education -- China; Poland
  - Exhibits, 1920; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    These exhibits detail feeding programs, infant mortality, American relief agencies in Europe and European applications that the Rockefeller Foundation had declined.
    Germany; Serbia; Europe; Hoover, Herbert
  - 1921, Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers) (Reel M Emb 1, Frame 641, Box 130)
    Medical education; Public health; United States
  - Conference Docket, 1921; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    Brief docket concerning various proposals for Rockefeller Foundation funding.
    United States; Public health; Medical education; Curie, Marie
  - Trip to China, 1921; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    Arranged by interview and visit, this diary documents the meetings and conferences Embree had with various professionals in the field of public health in China. The Rockefeller Foundation participates in public health and medical education.
    Public health; Medical education; China
  - 1922, Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Emb 1, Frame 948, Box 130)
    United States; Tuberculosis; Public health; Nursing; Medical education; Hygiene
  - Memos, 1921-1922; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    These memos contain notes on various conferences of Rockefeller Foundation proposed research and aid including program expansion, journal exchange, nursing education and building construction.
    East Asia; Dispensaries; China; Medical education; Nursing; Public health; United States; Europe; Hospitals; Hygiene; Japan
  - Memoranda, 1922; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    Arranged by interview and visit, this diary memoranda documents the meetings and conferences Embree had with various professionals in the field of public health in Asia.
    Medical education; Philippines; Public health; Singapore; China; East Asia; Hong Kong; Japan; Peking Union Medical College
  - 1923, Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers) (Box 131, Reel M Emb 2, Frame 1)
    Arranged by interview and visit, this diary documents the meetings and conferences Embree had with various professionals in the field of public health. The Rockefeller Foundation participates in public health and medical education. This diary documents a visit from the Japanese commission and a trip to Europe in July to gather information on nursing education, hospital organization and health facilities.
    Turkey; Public health; Serbia; Austria; Scotland; United States; Puerto Rico; Dispensaries; England; Belgium; Biology -- Research; Hookworm disease; Hospitals; Europe; France; Medical education; Poland; Hungary; Malaria; Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board
  - Exhibits, 1923; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation
    These exhibits are supplementary attachments to Embree's diary of his 1923 European trip.
    Turkey; Scotland; Serbia; Poland; Public health; Hungary; Nursing; France; Hospitals; England; Europe; Austria; Belgium
  - 1924, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Studies; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers) (Box 131, Reel M Emb 2, Frame 280)
    Arranged by interview and visit, this diary documents the meetings and conferences Embree had with various professionals in the field of public health. In 1924, Embree has become the newly created director of the Division of Studies. Its purpose is to administer work not included in existing units of the Rockefeller Foundation. The division focuses on work concentrated in human biology, nursing education, and hospital and dispensary studies.
    Canada; Dispensaries; Hospitals; Medical education; Nursing; Public health; United States
  - Memoranda, 1924; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Studies; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers)
    These memos augment the 1924 Diary.
  - 1925, Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Studies (Reel M Emb 2, Frame 611, Box 131)
    Arranged by interview and visit, this diary documents the meetings and conferences Embree had with various professionals in the field of public health. The mission of the Division of Studies is to administer work not included in existing units of the Rockefeller Foundation. The division focuses on work concentrated in human biology, nursing education, and hospital and dispensary studies.
    New Zealand; Medical education; Hospitals; Dispensaries; United States; Public health; Nursing; Australia; Canada
  - Memos, 1925; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Studies; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers)
    Memo of Interviews between Embree, Miss Goodrich, and Miss Clayton. File includes "Recommendations of the Conference on Nursing Education."
    Medical education; United States; Public health; Nursing
  - 1926, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Studies; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers) (Reel M Emb 2, Frame 779, Box 131)
    Arranged by interview and visit, this diary documents the meetings and conferences Embree had with various professionals in the field of public health. The mission of the Division of Studies is to administer work not included in existing units of the Rockefeller Foundation. The division focuses on work concentrated in human biology and nursing education. Embree surveys human biology university work and nursing education in Asia and Europe.
    France; Europe; Hospitals; Hawaii; Biology -- Research; Asia; England; China; United States; Universities and colleges; Public health; Human biology; Japan; Medical education; Nursing; Peking Union Medical College
  - Memoranda, 1926; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Studies
    Confidential Memorandum of Evening Conference with Dr. Raymond Pearl and Dr. Lawrence Henderson.
    Medical education; Physiology; Public health; United States
  - 1927, Rockefeller Foundation; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers) (Reel M Emb 2, Frame 970, Box 131)
    Edwin Embree becomes the Vice President of the home office of the Rockefeller Foundation in 1927. He travels to Europe and Central America to survey universities, health facilities and hospitals for Rockefeller Foundation programs. The diary is arranged by interview and visit.
    Sanitation; Scotland; United States; Medical education; Hygiene; Europe, Central; France; El Salvador; England; Honduras; Hungary; Germany; Guatemala; Panama; Nursing; Public health; Poland; Central America; Costa Rica; Nicaragua; Canada
- Evans, Roger F.
  - 1951-1952 (Box 132)
  - 1953 January-June (Box 132)
  - 1953 July-December (Box 132)
  - 1954 (Box 133)
  - 1955 January-June (Box 133)
  - 1955 July-December (Box 134)
  - 1956 A-K (Box 134)
  - 1956 L-Z (Box 134)
  - 1957 (Box 135)
  - 1958 (Box 135)
  - 1959 (Box 135)
- Everton, John Scott
  - 1972 February (Box 136)
  - 1972 March-April (Box 136)
  - 1972 May-September (Box 136)
  - 1972 October-December (Box 136)
  - 1973 January-May (Box 136)
    General note
    Missing as of 2008. No charge out in box.